In this video, I would like to talk about how to
在本节视频中我想介绍一下
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
evaluate a hypothesis that has been learned by your algorithm.
怎样评价通过你的学习算法得到的一个假设
In later videos, we will build on this
基于这节课的讨论 在之后的视频中
to talk about how to prevent in the problems of
我们还将讨论如何防止
overfitting and underfitting as well.
过拟合和欠拟合的问题
When we fit the parameters of our learning algorithm
当我们确定学习算法的参数时
we think about choosing the parameters to minimize the training error.
我们考虑的是选择参数来使训练误差最小化
One might think that getting a really low value of
有人认为 得到一个很小的训练误差
training error might be a good thing,
一定是一件好事
but we have already seen that
但我们已经知道
just because a hypothesis has low training error,
仅仅是因为这个假设具有很小的训练误差
that doesn't mean it is necessarily a good hypothesis.
并不能说明它一定是一个好的假设
And we've already seen the example of how a hypothesis can overfit.
我们也学习了过拟合假设的例子
And therefore fail to generalize the new examples not in the training set.
这时推广到新的训练样本上就不灵了
So how do you tell if the hypothesis might be overfitting.
那么 你怎样判断一个假设是否是过拟合的呢
In this simple example  we could plot the hypothesis h of x
对于这个简单的例子 我们可以
and just see what was going on.
画出假设函数h(x) 然后观察
But in general for problems with more features than just one feature,
但对于更一般的情况 特征不止一个的例子
for problems with a large number of features like these
就像这样有很多特征的问题
it becomes hard or may be impossible
想要通过画出假设函数来观察
to plot what the hypothesis looks like
就变得很难甚至不可能了
and so we need some other way to evaluate our hypothesis.
因此 我们需要另一种评价假设函数的方法
The standard way to evaluate a learned hypothesis is as follows.
如下给出了一种评价假设的标准方法
Suppose we have a data set like this.
假如我们有这样一组数据组
Here I have just shown  10 training examples,
在这里我只展示了10组训练样本
but of course usually we may have
当然我们通常可以有
dozens or hundreds or maybe thousands of training examples.
成百上千组训练样本
In order to make sure we can evaluate our hypothesis,
为了确保我们可以评价我们的假设函数
what we are going to do is split
我要做的是
the data we have into two portions.
将这些数据分成两部分
The first portion is going  to be our usual training set
第一部分将成为我们的训练集
and the second portion  is going to be our test set,
第二部分将成为我们的测试集
and a pretty typical split of this
将所有数据分成训练集和测试集
all the data we have into a training set and test set
其中一种典型的分割方法是
might be around say a 70%, 30% split.
按照7:3的比例
Worth more today to grade the training set
将70%的数据作为训练集
and relatively less to the test set.
30%的数据作为测试集
And so now, if we have some data set,
因此 现在如果我们有了一些数据
we run a sine of say 70%
我们只用其中的70%
of the data to be our training set where here "m"
作为我们的训练集
is as usual our number of training examples
这里的m依然表示训练样本的总数
and the remainder of our data
而剩下的那部分数据
might then be assigned to become our test set.
将被用作测试集
And here, I'm going to use the notation m subscript test
在这里 我使用m下标test
to denote the number of test examples.
来表示测试样本的总数
And so in general, this subscript test is going to denote
因此 这里的下标test将表示
examples that come from a test set so that
这些样本是来自测试集
x1 subscript test,  y1 subscript test is my first
因此x(1)test y(1)test将成为我的
test example which  I guess in this example
第一组测试样本
might be this example over here.
我想应该是这里的这一组样本
Finally, one last detail
最后再提醒一点
whereas here I've drawn this as though the first 70%
在这里我是选择了前70%的数据作为训练集
goes to the training set and the last 30% to the test set.
后30%的数据作为测试集
If there is any sort of ordinary to the data.
但如果这组数据有某种规律或顺序的话
That should be better to send a random 70%
那么最好是
of your data to the training set and a
随机选择70%作为训练集
random 30% of your data to the test set.
剩下的30%作为测试集
So if your data were already randomly sorted,
当然如果你的数据已经随机分布了
you could just take the first 70% and last 30%
那你可以选择前70%和后30%
that if your data were not randomly ordered,
但如果你的数据不是随机排列的
it would be better to randomly shuffle or
最好还是打乱顺序
to randomly reorder the examples in your training set.
或者使用一种随机的顺序来构建你的数据
Before you know sending the first 70% in the training set
然后再取出前70%作为训练集
and the last 30% of the test set.
后30%作为测试集
Here then is a fairly typical procedure
接下来 这里展示了一种典型的方法
for how you would train and test
你可以按照这些步骤训练和测试你的学习算法
the learning algorithm and the learning regression.
比如线性回归算法
First, you learn the parameters theta from the training set
首先 你需要对训练集进行学习得到参数theta
so you minimize the usual  training error objective j of theta,
具体来讲就是最小化训练误差J(θ)
where j of theta  here was defined using that
这里的J(θ)是使用那70%数据
70% of all the data you have.
来定义得到的
There is only the training data.
也就是仅仅是训练数据
And then you would compute the test error.
接下来 你要计算出测试误差
And I am going to denote the test error as j subscript test.
我将用J下标test来表示测试误差
And so what you do is take your parameter theta
那么你要做的就是
that you have learned from  the training set, and plug it in here
取出你之前从训练集中学习得到的参数theta放在这里
and compute your test set error.
来计算你的测试误差
Which I am going to write as follows.
可以写成如下的形式
So this is basically
这实际上是测试集
the average squared error
平方误差的
as measured on your test set.
平均值
It's pretty much what you'd expect.
这就是你期望得到的值
So if we run every test example through your hypothesis
因此 我们使用包含参数theta的假设函数对每一个测试样本进行测试
with parameter theta and  just measure the squared error
然后通过假设函数和测试样本
that your hypothesis has on your m subscript test, test examples.
计算出mtest个平方误差
And of course, this is the definition of the
当然 这是当我们使用线性回归
test set error if  we are using linear regression
和平方误差标准时
and using the squared error metric.
测试误差的定义
How about if we were doing a classification problem
那么如果是考虑分类问题
and say using logistic regression instead.
比如说使用逻辑回归的时候呢
In that case, the procedure for training
训练和测试逻辑回归的步骤
and testing say logistic regression is pretty similar
与之前所说的非常类似
first we will do the parameters from the training data,
首先我们要从训练数据 也就是所有数据的70%中
that first 70% of the data.
学习得到参数theta
And it will compute the test error as follows.
然后用如下的方式计算测试误差
It's the same objective function
目标函数和我们平常
as we always use but we just logistic regression,
做逻辑回归的一样
except that now is define using
唯一的区别是
our m subscript test, test examples.
现在我们使用的是mtest个测试样本
While this definition of the test set error
这里的测试误差Jtest(θ)
j subscript test is perfectly reasonable.
其实不难理解
Sometimes there is an alternative
有时这是另一种形式的测试集
test sets metric that might be easier to interpret,
更易于理解
and that's the misclassification error.
这里的误差其实叫误分类率
It's also called the zero one misclassification error,
也被称为0/1错分率
with zero one denoting that
0/1表示了
you either get an example right or you get an example wrong.
你预测到的正确或错误样本的情况
Here's what I mean.
我想说的是这个意思
Let me define the error of a prediction.
可以这样定义一次预测的误差
That is h of x.
关于假设h(x)
And given the label y as
和标签y的误差
equal to one if my hypothesis
那么这个误差等于1
outputs the value greater than equal to five
当你的假设函数h(x)的值大于等于0.5
and Y is equal to zero
并且y的值等于0
or if my hypothesis outputs  a value of less than 0.5
或者当h(x)小于0.5
and y is equal to one,
并且y的值等于1
right, so both of these cases basic respond
因此 这两种情况都表明
to if your hypothesis mislabeled the example
你的假设对样本进行了误判
assuming your threshold at an 0.5.
这里定义阈值为0.5
So either thought it was more likely to be 1, but it was actually 0,
那么也就是说 假设结果更趋向于1 但实际是0
or your hypothesis stored was more likely
或者说假设更趋向于0
to be 0, but the label was actually 1.
但实际的标签却是1
And otherwise, we define this error function to be zero.
否则 我们将误差值定义为0
If your hypothesis basically classified the example y correctly.
此时你的假设值能够正确对样本y进行分类
We could then define the test error,
然后 我们就能应用错分率误差
using the misclassification error metric to be
来定义测试误差
one of the m tests of sum from i equals one
也就是1/mtest 乘以
to m subscript test of the
h(i)(xtest)和y(i)的错分率误差
error of h of x(i) test
从i=1到mtest
comma y(i).
的求和
And so that's just my way of writing out that this is exactly
这样我就写出了我的定义方式
the fraction of the examples in my test set
这实际上就是我的假设函数误标记的
that my hypothesis has mislabeled.
那部分测试集中的样本
And so that's the definition of
这也就是使用
the test set error using the misclassification error
0/1错分率或误分类率
of the 0 1  misclassification metric.
的准则来定义的测试误差
So that's the standard technique for evaluating
以上我们介绍了一套标准技术
how good a learned hypothesis is.
来评价一个已经学习过的假设
In the next video,  we will adapt these ideas
在下一段视频中我们要应用这些方法
to helping us do things like choose what features
来帮助我们进行诸如特征选择一类的问题
like the degree polynomial to use with the learning algorithm
比如多项式次数的选择
or choose the regularization parameter for learning algorithm.
或者正则化参数的选择